<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2022-01-15T14:30:11-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/atom.xml</id><title type="html">Nathaniel Hamilton</title><subtitle>A website for learning more about Nathaniel Hamilton</subtitle><author><name>Nathaniel Hamilton</name></author><entry><title type="html">The Beginnings of Cafe Reviews</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/01/15/Intro-Cafe-Reviews.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Beginnings of Cafe Reviews" /><published>2022-01-15T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/01/15/Intro-Cafe-Reviews</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/01/15/Intro-Cafe-Reviews.html">&lt;p&gt;There is a new page to my website, &lt;a href=&quot;nphamilton.github.io/cafe-reviews/&quot;&gt;Cafe Reviews&lt;/a&gt;, where I provide my reviews of the various cafes I have visted in Nashville. Once I am able to travel again, I plan to add reviews for cafes I visit when I travel. Hopefully I’ll get a chance to visit many places and try all sorts of coffee. One of my dreams is to go back to Montreal and &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; get Tim Hortons coffee like I did the last time I was there. I was naive and did not realize that such famous cafes like &lt;a href=&quot;https://cafemyriade.com/&quot;&gt;Café Myriade&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Cafe Humble Lion&lt;/a&gt;. It is one of my biggest regrets that I thought Tim Hortons was the pinnicle of good coffee while I was there. I promise that I have learned better since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my cafe reviews I try to evaluate more than just the quality of the coffee served. I also rate food (if it is available) and the “vibe”. For the vibe, I am looking for “How much would I enjoy spending a few hours here to write, work on homework, or meet up with a friend?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to this new page, with its beautiful table of results, I will be adding a section to my blog posts where I write about my experience at whichever cafe I visit that week. I do not always get a chance to visit a cafe each week, so it will not be a regular addition to my blog, but I will add them as I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope my reviews are helpful for any coffee enthusiasts reading my posts!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Nathaniel Hamilton</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">There is a new page to my website, Cafe Reviews, where I provide my reviews of the various cafes I have visted in Nashville. Once I am able to travel again, I plan to add reviews for cafes I visit when I travel. Hopefully I’ll get a chance to visit many places and try all sorts of coffee. One of my dreams is to go back to Montreal and not get Tim Hortons coffee like I did the last time I was there. I was naive and did not realize that such famous cafes like Café Myriade and Cafe Humble Lion. It is one of my biggest regrets that I thought Tim Hortons was the pinnicle of good coffee while I was there. I promise that I have learned better since then.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Happy New Year!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/01/01/New-Year-resolution.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happy New Year!" /><published>2022-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/01/01/New-Year-resolution</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/01/01/New-Year-resolution.html">&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year!! 2021 was an eventful year and 2022 is looking to have even more big changes in store for my life. I am both excited and extremely nervous for the things to come. But first, I want to take a moment to reflect and review the last year before trying to wrap my head around the things to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;2021-in-review&quot;&gt;2021 in Review&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot happened this last year. I submitted 8+ papers to conferences and 3 got accepted. &lt;strong&gt;I got married&lt;/strong&gt;. I passed my Qualifying Exam, which upgraded me from a PhD student to a PhD candidate. I got vaccinated for COVID &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; managed to not get sick. All-in-all, an eventful year with some very big ups that were followed by some sharp downs as I crashed from exhaustion. I &lt;em&gt;do not&lt;/em&gt; recommend getting married the week before submitting 3 papers to a conference. It adds a ton of stress and hurts the quality of the papers being submitted. That being said, I thought it prudent to try and highlight some of the  things I did well as well as mark some things I still need to improve on. These can be used to help better inform the goals I create for myself in the new year, but I’ll be nice to myself and hold off on making it an exhaustive list of everything I need to work on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;things-i-did-well-and-am-proud-of&quot;&gt;Things I did well and am proud of&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I did a lot of writing that was praised for it’s coherency. All the reviews I received for my submitted papers commented on how well written the works were. I am proud of that since what good is a published paper if nobody understands it or wants to read it?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I married my beautiful, intelligent, caring, supportive wife Kendall. Every day I am reminded of how blessed I am that she said yes when I asked her to marry me &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; followed through with it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I passed my qualifying exam. It required selecting my committee, writing up a rough draft of my dissertation and proposal for new work (it was 79 pages), and giving an hour long presentation followed by intense questions from my committee. It was a ton of work to complete and I was so releived when they told me I passed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;things-i-need-to-work-on&quot;&gt;Things I need to work on&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting outside more often. Walking from the car to the lab is not enough time to properly appreciate how beautiful the world is outside my apartment/lab. I have dearly missed it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Writing more efficiently with fewer delays so I’m finishing papers before the day they are due.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allowing myself to take a break. Working non-stop until the project/paper is done can be necessary, but I rarely allow myself to rest without feeling immense guilt over it. I need to stop feeling so guilty about stepping away from the work so I have the energy to attack problems with 100% instead of forgoing the rest and only managing 40%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;my-goals-for-2022&quot;&gt;My Goals for 2022&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having reviewed my 2021, looking at my accomplishments, I have just a few goals going into the new year. A new year that will (hopefully) see me graduate with my PhD, secure a job, and potentially move to a new city&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The first 6 months of 2022 will be particularly busy as I try to finish up everything I need to graduate and get a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of my goals are directly related to things I need to do to graduate, and the rest I made in the hopes of improving my quality of life and/or addressing some of the things I need to work on. I’ve tried to make my goals qauntitative so at the end of the year I can look back a check off whether or not I met that goal or can assign a grade to how well I met it. Thus, my goals are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get at least 1 first author paper published.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Defend my dissertation and graduate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get a job in my field.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Walk outside more often; aiming to get at least 10,000 steps in every day like I used to.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue to blog once a week. Maybe start adding coffee shop reviews.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read at least one book every month and try to branch out into some more non-fiction titles.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take a vacation that lasts longer than a weekend.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Travel outside of Nashville for a reason that doesn’t involve visiting family&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wish me luck as I try to achieve all these goals and I hope you all have an amazing year where you achieve all the goals you set for yourself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I have loved my time in Nashville, but, as I’ve been looking into job postings, I haven’t found much around the city that fits. If I am to stay in Nashville, it will probably be for a fully remote job and I’m not sure that’s something I want. However, that’s a problem for a different day. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This goal is contingent on COVID numbers dropping again to a point where it is safe to travel. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Nathaniel Hamilton</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Happy New Year!! 2021 was an eventful year and 2022 is looking to have even more big changes in store for my life. I am both excited and extremely nervous for the things to come. But first, I want to take a moment to reflect and review the last year before trying to wrap my head around the things to come.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Post and Why I’m Blogging</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/12/30/First-Post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Post and Why I’m Blogging" /><published>2021-12-30T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/12/30/First-Post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/12/30/First-Post.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello World!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m starting this blog primarily for my own benefit. I often struggle with writers block associated with completing my research papers, which has pushed me further towards burning out and caused me to miss conference deadlines that I was shooting for. All-in-all, this is not good. To try and remedy my struggles with writing, I’m trying a new tactic: writing a weekly blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came to this decision after finding success with a similar solution to a different problem: &lt;strong&gt;I hated reading research papers&lt;/strong&gt;. For those that are not aware, grad students are constantly reading research papers and it is not a fun task. Some papers are better than others, but, generally, they are all very boring, and very dense. Since the whole point of reading research papers is to extract information and reading papers is what I spent ~80% of my time doing, I started to treat all my tasks with that mindset. That sucked a lot of the joy out of my life and, as a result, I started to hate reading. My developing hatred for reading led to a vicious spiral of guilt, frustration, and burnout. in short: I tried to stop reading and that led to problems and then greater frustrations with, and hatred for, reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did I overcome this hatred for reading? &lt;em&gt;I started reading novels again.&lt;/em&gt; It’s the age-old techinique of trying to find why you enjoyed doing something in the first place. I used to read voraciously as a kid and found so much joy in it. I just needed to find that spark again. So, I picked up a Percy Jackson book (one of my favorite series growing up) and tried to read it. After a slow start, I started to read more and more for longer periods of time. Now, I no longer dread having to read research papers and try to keep up with reading new novels every few weeks. An added benfit: my reading seed has gotten faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, I figure: might as well give it a try with writing. My friend Kristian Gumminger (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kgumminger?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Eauthor&quot;&gt;@kgumminger&lt;/a&gt;) started writing sports blogs and he seems to really enjoy it (it also got him a freelance gig writing two articles a week about the Kansas City Chiefs for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arrowheadpride.com/&quot;&gt;Arrowhead Pride&lt;/a&gt;). He’s inspired me to give it a try. So, I’ll be starting with writing about things I enjoy and am passionate about and see where things go from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Nathaniel Hamilton</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Hello World!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Earned a Master of Science from Vanderbilt University</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/highlights/2020/05/08/Masters-Graduation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Earned a Master of Science from Vanderbilt University" /><published>2020-05-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/highlights/2020/05/08/Masters-Graduation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/highlights/2020/05/08/Masters-Graduation.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/masters_diploma.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Master of Science Diploma&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Nathaniel Hamilton</name></author><category term="highlights" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>